No...
違う
No, no, no!
違う 違う 違う
If I just get a chance,
I can make any problem disappear!
（スバル）
きっかけさえあれば 何もかも
問題なんて消えてなくなる
This is wrong.
違う 俺はこんなことを
望んだんじゃ…
This isn't what I wanted...
Someone...
誰か…
Ram...
ラム
Petra...
ペトラ
No...
違う
It's not my fault!
俺のせいじゃ
It's not...
俺の…
Emi... lia...
エミ… リア
Ow!
You're too late.
（パック）
もう 遅すぎたんだよ
（カドモン･リッシュ）おい
Hey!
You listening?
聞いてんのか？
（スバル）えっ
Huh?
Don't "huh" me!
えっ じゃなくて
What's wrong with you? You suddenly spaced out.
どうした いきなり
ボケーっとして
Oh...
Subaru-kun?
（レム）スバルくん？
Subaru-kun!
スバルくん
（カドモン）おい
Hey!
What's wrong?
（レム）
どうしたんですか？
具合悪いんですか？
Do you feel ill?
Um...
あの…
Subaru-kun?
スバルくん…
Wait, Subaru-kun...
ちょっと スバルくん
どうしたんです？
Hey, come on.
What's wrong?
Not in front of my shop.
（カドモン）
店先で勘弁してくれ
Calm down...
落ち着いて
Subaru-kun?
スバルくん…
I'm pretty sure there's nyothing we can do.
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
これはもう お手上げって
言うしかにゃいかなー
Physical wounds are one thing,
but emotional scars are anyother story.
体の傷ならともかく
心はどうしようもにゃいから
Any idea what caused this?
（クルシュ･カルステン）
原因は分かっているのか？
No, I've checked every nook
and cranny of him, but...
（フェリックス）
いいえ 体の隅々まで
調べましたけど
What are the odds of it being a curse?
（クルシュ）
呪術のたぐいの可能性は
There's nyo indication of any
interference using mana.
マナ的に 変な干渉を受けた様子は
にゃいですね
If Ferris is unable to help,
フェリスが
力になれないのであれば―
no one in this household can heal him.
当家で
治療ができる者はいない
I'm sorry.
及ばず すまない
Oh, no.
いいえ こちらこそ
寛大なご配慮に言葉もありません
I cannot thank you enough
for your generous concern.
He's right. There's no mana interference.
（レム）
確かにマナの干渉はない
でも―
But...
The witch's miasma!
魔女の瘴気(しょうき)
Thank you for everything.
お世話になりました
In my master's stead, I thank you
for your kindness during our stay.
今日までのご厚意
主(あるじ)に代わり お礼を申し上げます
Pass this along to Emilia for me.
そちらもエミリアに
伝えてくれ
"Let us compete in a manner that
will bring neither of us shame."
互いに 己の魂に恥じぬ
戦いをしようと
Hey...
（フェリックス）ねえ
I know why you're returning to the mansion,
屋敷に戻るっていうのは
分かるけど 治す当てがあるの？
but can anyone there heal him?
He utters our names, if only occasionally.
時々ですけど
名前を口にするんです
My name, my sister's name...
レムの名前や姉様 それに―
And of course, Emilia-sama's.
エミリア様
If he sees her,
あのお方にお会いできたら
何か変化があるかもしれません
maybe his condition will change.
I realize this is tasteless, but I must ask.
不粋の極みだが
聞きたいことがある
How can you devote yourself
so much to Natsuki Subaru?
どうして卿(けい)は そこまで
ナツキ･スバルに尽くせる
Your relationship with him is unlike Ferris'
and mine, that of master and servant.
卿とナツキ･スバルの関係は―
私やフェリスのように
主従の関係ではない
But I must say
だが 卿のまなざしと働きは―
your behavior and the glances you cast
are those a woman gives a man.
男女のそれと
断ずるのも もどかしい
I am sorry.
いや すまない
今のは忘れてくれ
Forget I said—
No, it isn't that.
（レム）
いえ そういうわけでは
It's just... How can I put it?
ただ 何と言葉にしていいのか
Well...
そうですね…
I suppose it is because
スバルくんが
特別だからでしょうか
Subaru-kun is special.
Um...
（レム）あの…
Forgive me.
（クルシュ）
すまない 私としたことが
少し自失した
I was momentarily lost for words.
Natsuki Subaru is a lucky man.
ナツキ･スバルは果報者だな
That's for sure.
ホントに
If he ever recovers,
I'll have to tease him to the max!
元どおりになったら 意地でも
いじめ抜いてやんなきゃですね
Be well.
息災で
Good luck!
頑張ってねー
I know I mustn't let my personal
feelings interfere, but...
（レム）
本当は 私情を差し挟んだら
いけないはずなんですけどね
I felt a little happy to keep you
to myself at Crusch-sama's house.
クルシュ様の所で
スバルくんを一人占めできて―
ちょっぴりレムは
幸せに思っていたんです
I cannot do that at the mansion.
お屋敷では スバルくんを
独占なんてできませんから
Even though I knew that
something was troubling you.
スバルくんが悩んでいたのを
知っていたのに
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
Even though I heard that you'd
quarreled with Emilia-sama.
スバルくんがエミリア様と
口論したって そう聞いていたのに
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
I know you'll be all right, Subaru-kun.
大丈夫ですよね スバルくん
Because you are always...
スバルくんは いつだって―
鬼がかってる
すごい人なんですから
demoniacally possessed.
And you're a remarkable person.
It's far too quiet.
（レム）静かすぎる
あっ… ハア ハア…
（レム）今の 姉様
That was Sister!
I must return quickly.
早く戻らないと
Do not touch Subaru-kun!
スバルくんに触るな！
魔女教徒！
Witch cultists!
Huma!
ヒューマ！
Subaru-kun!
スバルくん
スバルくん！
You bastards...
お前… たちは―
You stole my sister's horn
姉様から角を奪い―
and with it, my reason to live, but that wasn't enough?
レムから 生きる理由を
奪っただけじゃ飽き足らず―
So now you've come here
今 この場で
死にゆく理由すら―
to steal my reason to die too!?
奪うのか！
I see...
（ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ）
なるほど
This is certainly interesting.
これはこれは 確かに
興味深いデスね
You wouldn't happen to be Pride, would you?
あなた もしや“傲慢”で
ありませんデスかね？
（ペテルギウス）
んー お答え頂けないようデスねー
I guess you're not going to answer me!
Ah, right...
ああー そうデスね
I haven't introduced myself yet.
私としたことが まだ挨拶を
していないではないデスか
I am a Sin Archbishop in the Witch Cult.
私は魔女教 大罪司教―
Archbishop of Sloth,
“怠惰”担当
ペテルギウス･ロマネコンティ―
Petelgeuse Romanée-Conti, at your service!
デス！
Ah, how comical...
（ペテルギウス）
ああ 滑稽なりデスね
What a very, very, very, very,
very entertaining sight!
なかなかなかなかなかなかに―
卿が乗る光景デス！
Truly, truly, truly!
実に実に実に―
My brain trembles...
脳が震える
Now, what has brought him here?
彼は何なのデスかね？
Dragon carriage...
（魔女教徒）竜車
A dragon carriage!
（ペテルギウス）
竜車　ああ 地竜はいいデスねえ
Ah, aren't land dragons great?
勤勉に従い 勤勉に働き―
They obey diligently, work diligently,
and play their role as a species diligently!
主として勤勉に努める姿勢が
すばらしいデス！
They're just fantastic!
Killed...
（魔女教徒）殺した…
Of course.
（ペテルギウス）なるほど
Your diligence brought the land dragon,
diligence itself, to the ground!
あなた方の勤勉さが―
地竜という 勤勉そのものの
生物を下した！
Ah, my brain trembles, trembles, trembles,
ああ 脳が震える
震える 震える―
trembles!
震えるー！
But a dead land dragon
is the very definition of "sloth."
しかし 死んだ地竜は
実に怠惰デスね
即座に現場の清掃を
Clean up the area at once.
With the day of the Ordeal upon us,
we mustn't allow our existence to be discovered.
来たる試練の日を目前に―
私たちの存在が露見することは
避けるのデス
同乗者は？
And his friend?
Unknown...
（魔女教徒）不明…
It is unknown if the girl is dead or alive?
少女の生死は不明
Unknown if she is dead or alive, you say?
生死 不明デスか
You are truly slothful, I say.
あなた 怠惰 デスね
With the forthcoming Ordeal,
you let a potential problem run free!
試練を前に 不安要素を残した！
Is this the sincerity you show
in return for our Gospel!?
それが福音に対する あなたの
真摯な報い方デスかー！
Ah, this is sloth...
ああ 怠惰だ…
Sloth, sloth, sloth, so very sloth!
怠惰怠惰怠惰怠惰ー
寵(ちょう)愛に背いた我らの怠惰を
お許しください
Please forgive us the sloth that
has led us to betray your goodwill!
愛に 愛に報いなければあー
Love...
We must repay love with love!
Bring the girl here.
少女をここへ
If she lives, kill her.
生きているなら 息の根を―
死んでいるなら その首を
連れてくるのデス！
If not, bring me her head!
Love!
愛に 愛に報いなければ
We must repay love with love!
Now...
さて
Now, now...
Now, now, now, now, now...
You will look into my eyes.
あなた―
私の目を見るのデス
Answer me.
答えるのデス
心して答えるのデス
And answer me carefully.
なぜ そんなに
体から漂ってくる―
Why does such dense love hang,
so abundant, upon your person?
濃密なまでの寵愛を
賜っているのか
福音書は
持っていないのデスか？
Do you not own a copy of the Gospel?
It saddens me to be ignored!
（ペテルギウス）
無視は寂しいデスね！
I'm treating you so kindly,
こんなにも 私は好意的に
接しているというのに
and yet, and yet, and yet,
and yet, yet, yet, yet, yet!
のにのにのににににに…
In that case, I will change
the order of my questions.
ならば 問いの順番を
変えることにするのデス
Let me ask you this...
お聞きするのデスが―
Why do you
あなた―
なぜ 壊れたふりなど
しているのデスか？
pretend that your mind has broken?
No, no, no, no.
I truly have my doubts.
実際のところ 疑問なのデスよ
Why and for what reason,
何故に 何のために
何の意味があって―
for what purpose, do you act crazed?
そんな狂気に染まったような
演技をしているのデスか？
Your insanity is far too sane.
あなたの狂気は正気にすぎる
そんな賢(さか)しげに おとなしく
同情を買うようにふるまうなど―
To behave so cleverly and quietly,
as if seeking sympathy...
狂気に対して
失礼というものデス
It is an insult to real madness.
You are a poorly-acted madman.
出来損ないの狂人の演技デス
本気でふるまうのであれば―
If you were truly mad,
you would pay the gazes of others no heed.
他者の目など
意識してはいけない
ああ 滑稽なり
滑稽なりデスねー！ ハハハハ
Ah, how comical!
How very comical!
I pity you!
あわれみ
惨めで醜くて卑賎(ひぜん)で矮(わい)小で
罪深いあなたを―
I pity your wretched, ugly,
lowly, diminutive, sinful being,
from the bottom of my heart!
私は 心よりあわれむのデス
Despite all that, you are so loved!
それほどまでに
愛されていながらー！
寵愛に報いず 停滞の中で
風化することを望むとは
You'd rather waste away in stagnation
than repay the goodwill shown to you?
あなた―
You...
are truly slothful.
怠惰デスねー
Oh?
おや？
I found you!
見つけました
Subaru-kun!
スバルくん！
How fantastic this is!
何とすばらしいことデスか！
A girl, a lone girl, is badly injured.
But still, she presses on!
少女が １人の少女が―
これだけ傷ついて
なお進むのデス
Enough of your nonsense, witch worshiper!
ご託は結構です 魔女教徒！
To carry out your insubordinate acts
あなた方は
ロズワール様の領地で―
in Roswaal-sama's domain
without permission, you are fools!
許可なく ふていを働く
しれ者ぞろい
In my absent master's stead, I, Rem,
この場にいない主に代わり
レムが誅(ちゅう)を下します！
shall carry out your death penalty!
In that battered state of yours?
そんなボロボロの
ご様子でですかー？
You have only come here to retrieve this boy.
そもそも あなたはこの少年を
連れ戻しに来ただけデス
You should refrain from saying things
that merely sound attractive.
聞こえのいい お飾りな言葉は
やめることデスよ
Don't touch him.
触るな…
Eh? What was that?
はい？ 何ですー？
Don't you dare touch him!
その人に 触るな！
ああ！ 今の叫びは
よかったデス！
That bellow just now was breathtaking!
Why does a devout believer
in love, such as yourself,
あなたほどの愛の信徒が 何故に
このような者に固執するのか
adhere to someone like him?
（レム）
お前にスバルくんの何が分かる！
You know nothing about Subaru-kun!
El Huma!
エルヒューマ！
（ペテルギウス）
ハッ ハッ すばらしい
すばらしいデス
Magnificent...
That was magnificent!
Rem...
（スバル）レム
My brain trembles.
脳が 震える
怠惰なる権能
Authority of Sloth:
Unseen Hand.
見えざる手 デス
見なさい 見るのデス
Look. You must witness.
あなたの行いの結果デス
Before you is the result of your actions.
あなたは何もせず 怠惰であった
By doing nothing, you practiced sloth.
And because of that, the girl is dead!
それ故に 少女は死んだのデス
あなたが！ 殺したのデス！
You killed her!
How awful! How very awful!
何という 何というー！！
You...
With my arm, with my fingers...
私の腕で 私の指で―
あなたが あなたがあなたが
あなたがあなたが―
You... You... You... You... You...
殺したのデス
killed her...
—op it...
（スバル）やめろ
ああ 痛い！ 痛い痛い痛い！
It hurts!
It hurts, it hurts!
助けて！ 助けて 助けて
ああ ああー
Help me! Help me!
Subaru-kun!
スバルくーん
Petelgeuse!
（スバル）ペテルギウスー！
I'll kill you! I'll kill you! I'll fucking kill you!
殺す！ 殺してやる！
Ah, I finally got you to call me by name.
ああ やっと名前を呼んで
頂けたようデスね
感無量デスよ
I'm deeply touched.
I'm gonna kill you! Kill you, hear me!?
殺してやる！ てめえは殺す！
死ね てめえ！
おらーっ！ 死ねよ！
Just die! Die, damn it!
（ペテルギウス）
ここは 随分と汚れて
しまいましたし―
This place is quite the mess now,
放棄するのデス
so I'll just leave it!
All right, men!
はいはーい
You will resume your duties.
あなた方は役割を続行
他の指と合流デス
Rendezvous with the other fingers.
試練の決行日は予定どおりデスね
The Ordeal will proceed as scheduled.
Now, as for your position in all this...
さてさて あなたの立場デスが
Bastard! I'll kill you! You're fucking dead!
I honestly have no idea what it is,
本当に分かりません
なので 判断は―
so I shall judge you as our Lord sees fit.
Damn you! Damn you!
み心に沿うことと
させて頂くとするのデス
I will leave you bound here.
つながれて 放置される
仮に あなたに福音が
もたらされたとしたら―
Should the Gospel happen
to find its way to you,
I am sure you will be saved.
あなたは助かるはずデスね
Damn you!
クソがー！
オホ オホ ホホホホホ…
オッホホホホ…
Damn you! I'll kill you!
I'm gonna kill you!
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
Oh?
おや？
Ah, you are also a believer in love.
ああ あなたも愛の信徒
そうデスね あなたは愛に殉じ
己の宿命にあらがったのデス
Yes, you sacrificed yourself for love,
defying your own fate.
But you fell before your
feelings reached him,
思い届かず 破れ
愛は行き場を失う
and your love had nowhere to go.
あなた 怠惰デスね
You are truly slothful!
I'll kill you! With my own bare hands!
殺す 殺す…
I'll kill you! I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
I'll kill you!
I'll kill you. I'll kill you. I'll kill you. I'll kill you.
（スバル）
殺す 殺す 殺す 殺す…
I'll kill you... I'll kill you.
I'll kill you. I'll kill you.
殺す 殺す 殺す 殺す
レム…
Rem?
Rem...
レム
Rem... Rem!
レム… レム！
Rem... Rem...
レム！ レム！ レム！ レム！
Rem! Rem!
Rem!
レムー！
Rem...
レム おい レム
Hey, Rem!
Hu...
ヒュー…
...ma.
Rem, you...
（スバル）レム お前…
Live...
（レム）生… き… て…
Rem...
レム 待って 俺を…
Wait, don't!
Live...
生… き… て…
大… 好… き…
Love... you...
Rem?
（スバル）レム…
Let's go, Rem.
行こう レム
Petelgeuse...
ペテルギウス
ペテルギウス…
ペテルギウス！
Petelgeuse!
Sleep...
（パック）眠れ
Along with my daughter.
我が娘と共に
（カドモン）おい
Hey!
You listening?
聞いてんのか？
（スバル）えっ
Huh?
Don't "huh" me!
えっ じゃなくて
どうした いきなり
ボケーっとして
What's wrong with you? You suddenly spaced out.
Oh...
Subaru-kun?
（レム）スバルくん？
Rem...
レム
Yes?
はい
What's the matter?
どうしたんですか？
まるで 死人に会ったような顔して
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Rem...
レム
は… はい
Y-Yes?
Rem...
レム
Yes?
はい
I...
俺は…
Look...
なあ
I hate to interrupt when
you're just getting heated up,
お熱いとこ悪いんだが―
but I can't run my business
with you two flirting there!
そこでイチャつかれると
商売にならん
（レム）
スバルくん ちょっといいですか？
Subaru-kun, can I ask something?
What is it?
（スバル）どうした？
Well, I may be mistaken.
いえ レムの勘違いかもしれません
It's just that, well...
ただ 少し―
The unpleasant smell on you
スバルくんから その―
seems to have grown stronger.
よくない香りが
強まった気がして
よくない香り… か…
Unpleasant smell, huh?
Okay, if you're uneasy, keep hold of my hand.
じゃあ ほら 不安なら
こうしてつかまえといてよ
Huh?
This feels a lot safer, right?
これなら安全な気がするだろ？
はい
Yes.
The  Faceof  Madness